Nasrin Nawa

Email: nasrinnawa94@gmail.com

Tel: 4028380415

Address: Lincoln, Nebraska 68503

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Story-driven journalist a depth at developing articles and investigating issues with tenacious and unwavering dedication. Offering seven years of experience in broadcasting and online media. Committed to working quickly with accuracy and knowledge of research, communication, web designing and editing programs. Self-motivated, detail-oriented, organized, engaging, media-savvy, fast learner and able to multi-task.

EDUCATION

January 2020 – present

UNIVERSITY OF LINCOLN NEBRASKA, COLLEGE OF JOURNALISM AND MASS COMMUNICATION

MA: Integrated media and communication,

Mar – Dec

KABUL UNIVERSITY, AFGHANISTAN, COLLEGE OF PSYCHOLOGY AND EDUCATIONAL SCIENCES

BA: Psychology GPA 3.7

JOB EXPERIENCE

Apr 4, 2022 – Apr 18

EXTERNAL MEDIA EXPERT, VOICE OF AMERICA, AFGHAN SERVICE

Write an evaluation report after reviewing six hours of TV & Radio shows plus online coverage during the fall of Kabul, Afghanistan

July 2018 – August 2021

MULTIMEDIA JOURNALIST, BBC PERSIAN

Produce and report live or recorded for BBC Persian channel in Kabul Write online stories for website

Oct 2017 - June 2018

MEDIA AND COMMUNICATION OFFICER, ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE OF THE PRESIDENT (AOP)

Manage all media contents of the office and create informative and persuasive content publishing in all the AOP media platforms including the official website Write monthly and annual reports/plans of media and communication department

Feb – July 2017

PRODUCTION MANAGER, ZAN TV

Manage and supervise production of 12 TV programs

Write and prepare TV program concepts

Liaison with all relevant internal and external departments such as marketing, technical, budget, quality, etc.

Jan 2017 - Apr 2018

PART TIME PRESENTER, 1TV MEDIA

Present a two-hour morning live show

Aug 2015 – Dec 2016

PART TIME PRESENTER/PRODUCER, 1TV MEDIA

Present and produce an informative-entertainment night show four nights a week Present and produce special events shows such as new year Produce materials for morning show

VOLUNTEER RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Nov 2016 – Mar 2017

RESEARCH ASSISSTANCE, Lynne Donnel, Independent Britain Researcher Field and library research about the situation of Afghan women in Afghanistan Interview and collect materials Sep – Nov 2014

RESEARCHER, NATIONAL CENTER FOR POLICY RESEARCH (NCPR), KABUL UNIVERSITY.

Conduct research about lack of book reading culture among Kabul University students

SKILLS:

- Research
- Crisis management, PR, and communication
- Strategic planning
- Press releases writing
- Advertising and marketing skills
- News writing, articles, and reports
- Strong understanding of target audience and industry trends
- Public speaking and presenting
- Creativity, adaptability, and teamwork
- Web designing skill (HTML, CSS, Java script)
- Adobe XD and Premier
- Ethical journalism
- Self-motivated and quick learner
- Multitasking and able to work under tough deadlines

REFERENCE

Shoaib Sharifi / Editor, BBC World Service, Kabul Bureau

Tel: +93 700277237

Email: shoaib.sharifi@bbc.co.uk